Jerry Shiuan-Yih Ho

1010 West Peachtree Street NW #657, Atlanta, GA, 30309 | 347-493-7957 | x.jerryho@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer, with 6+ years of experience developing integrations with eCommerce, Social Media, and Marketing platforms. Pursuing a Full-Stack Developer position to utilize my extensive coding experience and build a career. I will be relocating to Los Angeles by August 2019.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | EMORY UNIVERSITY | MAY 2018

Atlanta, GA

- Major: Computer Science
- Second Major: Music Vocal Performance
- QuestBridge Scholar (QSN), Dean's List
- Study Abroad: University of Adelaide, South Australia

July 2015- November 2015

SKILLS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, DynamoDB

Languages: Python (Advanced), C (Proficient), Ruby (Advanced), AngularJS/Angular 7 (Advanced), Javascript, Java (Advanced), x86 assembly, Go (Familiar), PHP (Familiar)

Design: HTML, CSS, Photoshop, Lightroom, WordPress

Frameworks/Tools: AWS, Heroku, Sidekiq, Docker, Linux, ElasticSearch, Redis, MVC

Testing: RSpec, Teaspoon, Jenkins, CircleCI

Other: eCommerce, Email Deliverability, SendGrid, Bugsnag, Github, JIRA, AJAX, Agile

WORK EXPERIENCE

Springbot – eCommerce Marketing Automation Platform

Atlanta, GA

DevOps/Software Engineer (40 hours/week)

May 2018 – Present

- Actively participated in a Scrum based development process with a diverse team of developers and stakeholders
- Developed a trial version of Springbot, automating the integration and onboarding of Shopify customers
- Planned, designed and built an automated customer offboarding tool that saved thousands of person-hours company wide
- Profiled and optimized data with Redis, ElasticSearch, MongoDB, PostgreSQL and Sidekiq across multiple products
- Actively managed and monitored cloud infrastructure AWS (EC2, S3), Redis, Sidekiq
- Documented and normalized deployment processes to Heroku, AWS and Sidekiq
- Developed integrations with Shopify, Magento, WooCommerce, BigCommerce, Amazon, AdRoll, Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, MailChimp, and Constant Contact
- Mentored and onboarded new hires on company processes, development best practices, and DevOps tools

Software Development Intern (35 hours/week)

June 2017 - May 2018

- Automated customer onboarding processes, reducing onboarding time by more than 60%
- Wrote, tested, debugged, and peer reviewed production level features in scrum team
- Developed custom integrations for VIP customers to increase customer retention

Jerry Shiuan-Yih Ho

1010 West Peachtree Street NW #657, Atlanta, GA, 30309 | 347-493-7957 | x.jerryho@gmail.com

Jerry Ho Photography

Atlanta, GA

Emory University Campus Photographer / Freelance Photographer September 2014 – Present

- Photograph various student and faculty events at Emory University
- Provide portraits for corporate events, headshots, weddings, and family sessions
- Complete digital image processing with Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop

Schwartz Performing Arts Center | Emory University

Atlanta, GA

Stage Technician / Audio-Visual Operator

November 2014 – December 2017

• Set and striked stage sets and managed lighting and sound equipment to create optimal acoustics and visual aesthetics to ensure efficient performances

SELECTED COURSEWORK

- Database Systems (MySQL, Java, JDBC, PHP)
 - Studied database design, relational databases, functional dependences, normalization, and client/server programming
- Artificial Intelligence (Python)
 - o Implemented Pac-man agent with search, reinforcement learning, classification, and probabilistic inference algorithms
- Software Engineering Practicum (Ruby, AWS, Agile, HTML, CSS, Data Mining)
 - Product managed a scrum team of five on a Rails app called PDRank to help medical professionals query relevant PDF documents based on symptoms
- Computer Security (C, Assembly)
- Systems Programming (C, Unix)
- Theory of Computation
- Data Structures and Algorithms (Java)
- Coursera Python for Everybody Specialization

LEADERSHIP AND COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

- Director of Member Development, Social Media/Public Relations, *Delta Tau Delta Fraternity*, *Beta Epsilon Chapter*, 2015-2017
- Representative at Large, *Emory Quest Scholars* (QSN), 2014-2016
- Treasurer, AHANA A Cappella, 2013-2015
- Emory Concert Choir/Stageworks 2014-2018
- Mu Phi Epsilon Professional Music Fraternity, Delta Zeta Chapter 2017-2018
- Emory Gymnastics
- International Service Advocate, Ebenezer Mission Church, 2010-2016

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Links: Github: /mrjerryho LinkedIn: /mrjerryho Website: jerryhophotography.com
- **Recent Reading:** Site Reliability Engineering, Ng-Book, The Twelve Factor App
- Language Skills: English (Native), Mandarin Chinese (Advanced)
- Other Interests: Photography, Acoustics, Opera, Travel, Calisthenics, Scuba Diving
- Citizenship: US Citizen